FFmpeg, an open source command line tool for processing audio
and video files. It was created by Fabrice Ballard in the year 2000.
The name stands for Fast forward, followed by the Moving Picture Experts Group file
format. Today, it's used in a wide variety of tools like Google Chrome and
Blender, as well as video platforms like YouTube and Vimeo. It's able
to decode, encode, transcode, multiplex, Demultiplex,
Stream, filter, and play virtually any multimedia file in the world with
over 100 different codecs supported. It works by taking an input file,
then passes it to a demultiplexer that splits the audio
and video tracks into separate encoded data packets. These packets are then
decoded into uncompressed frames, which can be further processed and
filtered. You might modify the brightness and contrast, add subtitles,
or visualize the audio as a waveform. Then finally, these frames are encoded
and multiplexed back into the output file. In addition, it also comes
with the FF Play tool to easily play media from the command line and
FF probe to extract metadata from a file, in addition to tons of
low level libraries for developers building their own multimedia processing
software. To get started, install it, then open up the terminal,
use the FFmpeg command followed by I to supply one
or more input files. To convert that file to a different format,
simply provide the name of the output. It will automatically detect the file
extension and convert it to the proper codec. Or the CFlag can be used
to specify an explicit codec like MPEG four for the video track and
MP3 for the audio. You may also want to change the quality of the output
file. The B flag can change the bitrate, while the R
flag can change the frame rate and S can change the resolution. In some
cases, you may have multiple video clips that need to be combined together.
These clips can be listed in their own text file, then combined together by
specifying the format as Concat and the codec as copy.
Copy can also be used to make modifications to a video, like when used with
T to trim a certain number of seconds off of the video footage.
But the most powerful option might be VF, which creates a filter
graph that can handle transformations like rotation and scaling,
and color modifications like brightness and contrast, in addition to
many other effects. And if you have an SRT file for captions in your video,
FFmpEg is able to convert it to an as file, which can
then be used with the VF option to easily add subtitles to
your video. This has been FFmpeg in 100 seconds.
Hit the like button for more short videos like this. Thanks for watching, and I
will see you in the next one.
FFmpeg, an open source command line tool for processing audio and
video files. It was created by Fabrice Ballard in the year 2000.
The name stands for Fast forward, followed by the Moving Picture Experts
Group file format. Today, it's used in a wide variety of tools like
Google Chrome and Blender, as well as video platforms like YouTube and Vimeo.
It's able to decode, encode, transcode, multiplex,
Demultiplex, Stream, filter, and play virtually any multimedia file in
the world with over 100 different codecs supported. It works by taking an
input file, then passes it to a demultiplexer
that splits the audio and video tracks into separate encoded data
packets. These packets are then decoded into uncompressed frames, which can
be further processed and filtered. You might modify the brightness and contrast,
add subtitles, or visualize the audio as a waveform. Then finally,
these frames are encoded and multiplexed back into the output
file. In addition, it also comes with the FF Play tool to easily play
media from the command line and FF probe to extract metadata from a
file, in addition to tons of low level libraries for developers building their
own multimedia processing software. To get started, install it,
then open up the terminal, use the FFmpeg command followed by
I to supply one or more input files. To convert that file to
a different format, simply provide the name of the output. It will automatically detect
the file extension and convert it to the proper codec. Or the CFlag can
be used to specify an explicit codec like MPEG four for the video track
and MP3 for the audio. You may also want to change the quality of
the output file. The B flag can change the bitrate,
while the R flag can change the frame rate and S can change the
resolution. In some cases, you may have multiple video clips that need
to be combined together. These clips can be listed in their own text file,
then combined together by specifying the format as Concat and
the codec as copy. Copy can also be used to make modifications to
a video, like when used with T to trim a certain number of seconds off
of the video footage. But the most powerful option might be VF, which creates
a filter graph that can handle transformations like rotation and scaling,
and color modifications like brightness and contrast, in addition to many
other effects. And if you have an SRT file for captions in your video,
FFmpEg is able to convert it to an as file, which can then be used
with the VF option to easily add subtitles to your video.
This has been FFmpeg in 100 seconds. Hit the like button for more
short videos like this. Thanks for watching, and I will see you in the next
one.